23 Van Wagenen Ave, Apt# 2, Jersey City, NJ 07306 USA | Phone: +1 551-229-2663 | LinkedIn | Email | Portfolio

#### Summary

Software professional with an industrial experience mainly focusing on AngularJS, UI Development and JavaSript technologies. Worked extensively on software testing, scripting languages, maintenance and implementation based on existing software. Hard working and detail oriented professional with strong analytical and critical thinking abilities.

#### Education

# Wilmington University, Delaware

Jan 2016 - Dec 2018

Masters of Science, Information Systems Technologies

#### **Technical Skills**

**Web Development**: Angular 2/4/6/7/8/9/10/11, Express.js, JavaScript, jQuery, JavaScript framework, ECMAScript ES5/ES6+, Ember.js, Next.js, Vue.js Web API, CSS/CSS3/Sass, Semantic, Bootstrap, HTML/HTML5, REST API, Swagger, Node.js/NPM, Webpack, RxJs **Databases**: Microsoft SQL, Oracle PL/SQL, mongo DB

Languages: Shell Scripting, Visual Basic, Assembly Language, Python, PHP, JSON, XML

Methodologies: OOP/D, UML, MVC

Others: Adobe Flash, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD/illustrator, Visual Studio, MS Project, GitHub, Docker, Grunt & Gulp, Protractor, NPM, native

DOM, Event APIs

### **Professional Experience**

### Bank of America, Jersey City, NJ

June 2020 – Current

UI/Web Developer

- Responsible for analyzing, mocking, and giving shaping UI design as desire and implement it using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery/JavaScript, AngularJS.
- Performed test execution on SIT and UAT server using real time data, also got tasks for writing JUNIT test cases.
- Working closely with the User Experience Designer, performing optimized tests to increase conversion and user engagement.
- Developed and performed test cases using jasmine and Karma in the unit test, and used Http-server for the End2End testing.

# Dun & Bradstreet, Center Valley, PA ( <a href="https://www.iresearch.dnb.com">https://www.iresearch.dnb.com</a> )

Jan 2019 - June 2020

UI/Web Developer

- Presented an architecture for upgrading Angularis 1.9 to Angular 11 using hybrid approach and updated full application using Angular 11 as main front end framework to create views to hook up models to the DOM and synchronize data with server as a Single Page Application.
- Responsible for writing and executing TDD and BDD based automation scripts for UI end to end testing using ES6, Protractor, Selenium and Cucumber for automation testing.
- Responsible for mocking and giving shaping front-end as desire using HTML, CSS, jQuery/JavaScript/ES6, Angular 11, Angular CLI for creating components, Services, pipes, Directives.
- Used Angular 11 Template Driven forms and Modern Driven (Reactive) forms to perform form validations. Worked on some of the new features like new if else syntax, ng-templates, and form validators.

#### Anthem Inc, Norfolk, VA

Aug 2018 – Dec 2018

UI/Front-End Developer

- Responsible for developing SPA by writing well-structured, easily maintainable and well-documented code using HTML 5.0, CSS3, SCSS, jQuery, AngularJS and JavaScript and jQuery. Created Custom Directives, filters, made use of Modules, and \$http service from controller.
- Utilized AngularJS to bind HTML template to JavaScript object & performed Parent & Activity provider UI designs, from concept through final product release for web and mobile applications in responsive design.

### SQA Labs, Glendale, AZ

April 2018 – July 2018

UI Developer/UX Designer

- Developed prototype concepts using Axure, Photoshop, and Illustrator concept designs.
- Developed new prototypes and implemented those prototypes using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML and CSS.
- Responsible for creating JavaScript code for different modules.

# Perseverance Software's Pvt. Ltd, India (<a href="http://perseverance.in/">http://perseverance.in/</a>)

Jan 2014 – Jan 2016

UI/UX Designer (Web Developer)

- Responsible for designing, maintaining, and updating website using JavaScript, J-query, PHP and HTML, bootstrap.
- Designed user-centered Web sites with sophisticated production values and intuitive navigation to maximize user engagement.